{"test_questions": [[{"question": "In DNA sequencing, the primer", "opta": "specifies where the sequence ends", "optb": "specifies where the sequence begins", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "generates variety of different sized fragments", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The chromosome of almost all bacteria is in the shape of", "opta": "an open circle", "optb": "helix", "optc": "a closed circle", "optd": "a linear chromosome", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In which of the following uracil is present?", "opta": "RNA", "optb": "DNA", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "To which of the following adenine always binds?", "opta": "Guanine", "optb": "Cytosine", "optc": "Thymine", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Guanine always binds to", "opta": "cytosine", "optb": "guanine", "optc": "thymine", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The function of ribosomes within the cell is", "opta": "to produce ATP", "optb": "to ferment carbohydrates", "optc": "to synthesize proteins", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "According to base pairing rules the bases of one strand match-up with the bases of the second strand of DNA and the two strands are said to be", "opta": "complementary", "optb": "oppositely charged", "optc": "identical", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "RNA that is complementary to a segment of another RNA molecule to which it will bind is known as", "opta": "missense RNA", "optb": "antisense RNA", "optc": "nonsense RNA", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is not an essential part of a two-component phosphorelay system?", "opta": "Response regulator", "optb": "Sensor kinase", "optc": "Autoinducer", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The DNA that actually codes for a protein's primary structure in eukaryotes is", "opta": "the entire gene", "optb": "portions of the gene called introns", "optc": "portions of the gene called exons", "optd": "the promoter", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Stem and loop structures are", "opta": "proteins that help partially denatured enzymes to recover their native configuration", "optb": "structures in DNA caused by inverted repeats", "optc": "structures at the ends of linear eukaryotic DNA molecules", "optd": "the bonds between adjacent DNA nucleotides in the same strand", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}